http://www.wineaustralia.com/privacy

Bulk wine
Wine Australia Licensing and Approval System (WALAS)
Bulk wine
Wine Australia Licensing and Approval System (WALAS)
Quick navigation
Introduction The kinds of personal information we collect How we collect personal information How we hold personal information How we use personal information collected by you Who we may disclose your information to Access, correction and erasure of your personal information Anonymity/pseudonymity Information that may be collected automatically - IP addresses and Cookies Security Your privacy choices and how to make a complaint Changes to this Privacy Policy Contact information and Policy updates Modify your cookie consent
1. Introduction Wine Australia (‘we’ or ‘us’ or ‘our’), a statutory body established under the Wine Australia Act 2013 (Cth), (ABN 89 636 749 924) is bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Privacy Act) which dictates how we collect, store and use your personal information.   Because we conduct some activities globally, we are also bound by various international laws relating to privacy and data protection. For example, we are required to comply with the EU General Data Protection Regulation when dealing with personal information of EU citizens. Accordingly, Wine Australia has adopted a comprehensive privacy policy capturing the requirements in all markets in which it operates. ‘Personal information’ is information about an identifiable individual, as defined by applicable law. We are committed to protecting the privacy of any personal information we hold about individuals in accordance with the applicable laws. As such, we only collect personal information where it is reasonably necessary for us to do so in performing our statutory functions and related activities. This policy explains how we handle the personal information we collect and receive from you through use of our websites and mobile applications (‘Sites’), and other digital or offline services controlled by Wine Australia that refer to this Privacy Policy (collectively, ‘Our Services’). In addition, this policy sets out the rights and obligations of both you and Wine Australia in relation to the handling of your personal information, and how you can request access to, correction or deletion of your personal information we hold. 2. The kinds of personal information we collect In conducting our statutory role and associated activities, we may collect and hold and hold your personal information if:
you sign-up or participate in an event being run by us you subscribe to communication disseminated by us you contribute to or participate in a survey run by us you use Our Services you are a licensed exporter of wine from Australia you are pay a charge or levy through which we are funded we procure goods and/or services from you or through your employer or principal, or you are employed by us.
The types of personal information we collect and hold will depend on the nature of your dealings with us and may (but does not always) include:
your name, gender and date of birth any information about you which you provide through promotions, competitions or customer surveys information collected as part of a levy return process your personal and/or work contact information – including postal and residential address, telephone numbers and email addresses information provided by you to us via our licensing and approval system (WALAS) information about your commercial or business operations within the wine sector information about any regional association that you are a member of your credit card or account details (during the course of conducting financial transactions with you) Australian Business Numbers (which are only used in accordance with the Privacy Act), and your opinion on issues relating to the wine sector.
If necessary, we may also ask you to provide it with additional personal information from time to time, including when you call us. We will always ask you for permission to collect your personal information prior to collecting it. 3. How we collect personal information We may collect personal information from you with consent in the following ways:
when you access or request information from our Sites through the Wine Australia Licensing and Approval system (WALAS) when you participate in a competition or trade promotion conducted by us or one of our related companies when you participate in a survey from you in person at trade shows, road shows, seminars and events through social media sites, apps and e-commerce platforms in other correspondence with you or your agents, employees or subcontractors when you lodge a return through our system in accordance with the requirements of the Primary Industries Levies and Charges Collection Act 1991 (Collection Act) and the Primary Industries Levies and Charges Collection Regulations 1991 (Collection Regulations), and in performing our statutory functions.
4. How we hold personal information We hold personal information in physical records, on our information management system or on mailing lists. We take reasonable steps to hold all hard copy and electronic records of your personal information in a secure manner to ensure that it is protected from misuse, interference and loss, and unauthorised access, modification or disclosure. 5. How we use personal information collected from you We collect, use and exchange your information for the purpose of:
performing our statutory functions managing our relationship with you responding to your enquiries facilitating the collection of the Wine Export Charge, giving statements of export required to be provided under the regulation 5 of Schedule 35 of the Collection Regulations and assisting you in submitting returns as required under the Collection Regulations where you have given us your consent, providing you with (or permitting selected third parties to provide to you with), information on services, events and activities run by Wine Australia where you have given us your consent, updating you on issues relating to the wine sector (for example, through distribution of various newsletters) conducting specific projects in which you have chosen to participate administering events and competitions analysing and improving the services (and content) we offer and the events and activities we undertake personalising the way that our online content is presented to you and to allow you to participate in interactive features when you choose to do so to carry out our obligations arising from contracts entered into between you and us, and any other purposes notified to you at the time your personal information is collected.
Marketing You may also choose to receive marketing information from us, such as offers regarding Our Services, invitations, or other notifications and offers. In circumstances where we have obtained your consent, we will use your contact and other personal information to contact you at any time in the future to:
provide you with information and updated information about Our Services; obtain sponsorships, provide training and other educational activities, seek consultancy services or to contact you for surveys; and/or communicate with you in relation to any other matters in respect of which you have consented to Wine Australia contacting you.
At any time, you may opt out of the use of your personal information for marketing purposes by contacting us at the contact details set out below or by using the unsubscribe mechanism in the relevant marketing material you receive from us. 6. Who we may disclose your information to Your personal information may be disclosed:
where the use or disclosure is required at law to Wine Australia’s related entities, International offices and representatives (for the purpose of Wine Australia’s function and activity only) to the Australian Government Department of Agriculture, Water and the Environment for the purpose of facilitating the administration and collection of the Wine Export Charge specialist advisors to Wine Australia who have been engaged to provide Wine Australia with legal, administrative, financial, insurance, research, marketing or other services where you have given us consent to avoid, lessen or prevent a serious emergency or crime. (If we use or disclose personal information about you in those circumstances we will make a written record of such use or disclosure) to contractors who provide services to us, including database contractors located overseas to third party companies which Wine Australia may have commercial or non-commercial relationships with for the purpose of promoting wine events and products, and any other person authorised implicitly or expressly, when the personal information is provided or collected by us.
7. Access, correction and erasure of your personal information You may request access to, correction or erasure of your personal information at any time by emailing us at enquiries@wineaustralia.com. You may also object to data processing for the purposes of profiling used for business interests. There is no requirement for you to provide a reason for such request. We may deny access to personal information where we are required by law to withhold the information, or where the requested access would compromise the privacy of others. 8. Anonymity/pseudonymity You have a general right to anonymity/pseudonymity when dealing with us. However, if you do not provide us with the personal information that we request, our ability to provide services to you may be diminished. 9. Information that may be collected automatically - IP addresses and Cookies We use cookies and collect IP addresses. An IP address is a number that can uniquely identify a specific computer or other network device on the internet from visitors to our Sites. Consequently, we may collect technical data from you as well as other related information about your device, systems, application software, and peripherals. Some of this information may be capable of personally identifying you. Cookie options When using our corporate website (wineaustralia.com), you will have the following options below in relation to tracking technologies such as cookies (‘Cookie Options’):
Accept All Cookies: This is our default system level and allows the Site’s optimum functionality. It allows all cookies, including third-party cookies, to track your device. You may alter your consent to any of the other two Cookie Options at any time. Essential cookies are cookies which are required for all necessary Site functionality. This includes authentication, language selection etc. Your device will not be tracked. You may alter your consent to any of the other two Cookie Options at any time. Deny all cookies and tracking means you do not consent to any cookie tracking. Please note that some cookies are essential to the functioning of our Sites and deleting or disabling them will reduce Site functionality.
Digital Asset Library When using our digital asset library (wineaustralia.imagegallery.me), which is hosted on a platform owned by a third party provider, your user's IP address, navigational and ordering information may be collected. The platform uses cookies for functionality such as basic search, browsing, placing orders, retrieving previous transactions and save assets to work correctly. Cookies on this platform are necessary for providing each registered user access to their own personal information. A user may delete or disable the use of cookies on our digital asset library, at any time, via browser settings. When a user first registers to use our digital asset library, the user is asked for permission to use cookies. At that point, the user can decline the request and cancel the registration submission. A registered user may also deregister their account at any time. Click here for more information about cookies used on our digital asset library. In some cases, third parties such as Google Analytics may use cookies on our communication channels in connection with online services like Site analytics, surveys and advertising. This may allow them to collect information about your use of our resources, which they may store in countries other than Australia. If you do not want your information used by Google Analytics, you can install the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at the Google Analytics opt-out page. 10. Security Wine Australia has taken reasonable steps regarding physical and technical access intrusion security measures to protect the personal information we hold against loss, misuse, interference and from unauthorised access, alteration or disclosure. However, if you are considering sending us any personal information through any of our communication channels, please be aware that the information may be insecure in transit, particularly where no encryption is used (e.g. email, standard HTTP). You must also take care to protect your usernames and passwords and notify us as soon as possible if you become aware of any security breaches. Where there is a data breach that is likely to cause serious harm Wine Australia is required to notify individuals and the relevant authorities, unless remedial action has been taken. We will manage these in accordance with the Privacy Act 1988, and any other relevant laws and regulations in force at the time, together with with this Privacy Policy and our internal policies and procedures related to the protection of personal information and security incident response plans. 11. Your privacy choices and how to make a complaint You may contact us at any time if you have questions about this Privacy Policy or the personal information we collect about you. Under applicable privacy laws, you may be entitled to request access to and/or rectify, remove your personal information, or object to any use of your personal information. If you wish to make a complaint about a breach of this Privacy Policy or the Australian Privacy Principles of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) you can contact us at enquiries@wineaustralia.com. You will need to provide us with all relevant details of your complaint and any supporting evidence.
We will refer your complaint to our Privacy Officer who will investigate your complaint and determine the steps that we will undertake to resolve it. We will contact you if we require any additional information from you and will notify you, in writing, of the outcome of the investigation. If you are not satisfied with our determination, you can contact us to discuss your concerns or contact to the Australian Privacy Commissioner via the contact details set out below. 12. Changes to this Privacy Policy This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time so you should check it each time Our Services refer to this Privacy Policy. The date of the most recent revisions will appear at the bottom of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with theapplicable version at the time of using Our Services, please do not continue to use our Services. If you do continue to use our communication platforms, you accept the terms of our updated Privacy Policy. If material changes are made to our Privacy Policy we will notify you by placing a notice on Our Sites. CONTACT INFORMATION AND POLICY UPDATES If you have questions or complaints about our privacy practices or procedures or if you would like to request to access, correct or amend any personal information that Wine Australia holds about you, please contact our Privacy Officer in writing at:
Email:
enquiries@wineaustralia.com
Postal Address:
Wine Australia Attention: Privacy Officer Corner Botanic Road and Hackney Road Adelaide, South Australia 5000 Australia
We will do our best to respond to all reasonable requests in a timely manner. For information about privacy generally, or if you are unsatisfied with our handling of your request or resolving your concerns, you may lodge a complaint with The Office of the Australian Information Commissioner on 1300 363 992 or via www.oaic.gov.au.
Modify your cookie consent
The website now stores cookies on your computer. You may restrict this to using only some of them or none, however you may not be able to use certain features of the website including but not limited to: sign up, log in, submitting any forms, see personalised content.
Stay in touch with Wine Australia
Please enter your first name
Please enter a valid email address
Submit
Follow us on
Facebook Wechat Instagram YouTube LinkedIn
@Wine_Australia
About Wine Australia
Our BoardOur teamOur values RelationshipsStrategy and planningPerformance and reportingCareers
News
Media releasesLatest newsDigital Asset Library
Pay my account Forms & templates Wine facts Login to WALAS Wine Watch Fraud Reporting
AustralianWine.com Contact Wine Australia
Call +61 8 8228 2000 Fax +61 8 8228 2066 Email us
Australian Government | Australian Grape and Wine Authority
© 2020 Wine Australia. ABN: 89 636 749 924   I  Disclaimer  I  Privacy  I  Copyright  I  FOI and Information Publication Scheme  I Index lists of files I  Senate Order Contract Listing |  Site map I  Public Interest Disclosures I  Compliments and complaints
This content is restricted to wine exporters and levy-payers. Some reports are available for purchase to non-levy payers/exporters.
Levy payers/exporters Sign in or Register
Non-levy payers/exporters Find out what you can purchase
This content is restricted to wine exporters and levy-payers. Some reports are available for purchase to non-levy payers/exporters.
Levy payers/exporters Update your account details
Non-levy payers/exporters Find out what you can purchase
